Guide to the Theodore Rockwell Papers 1915-2013
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Nuclear Power, 1915-2013; Series VII
  - Robinson, Arthur, Access to Energy, 1978-2000 (Box-folder 53.4)
  - Robinson, Arthur, Access to Energy, 2000-2007 (Box-folder 53.5)
  - Robinson, Arthur, Access to Energy, 2007-2012 (Box-folder 54.1)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Heresy, Excommunication and Other Weeds in the Garden of Science", 1981 (Box-folder 54.2)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Isotope Dope", circa 1950 (Box-folder 54.3)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Nuclear Facts Report", 2009 (Box-folder 54.4)
  - Rockwell Publication: "Nuclear Power: The Cursed Gift", 2010 (Box-folder 54.5)
  - Rockwell Publication: Power to the People, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 54.6)
  - Rockwell Publication: Power to the People Draft Reviews, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 54.7)
  - Rockwell Publication: Power to the People Draft Reviews, 1994 (Box-folder 54.8)
  - Rockwell Publication: Power to the People Draft Reviews, 1995 (Box-folder 55.1)
  - Rockwell Publication: Power to the People Draft Reviews, 1995 (Box-folder 55.2)
  - Rockwell Publication: "We're Planning the Wrong Future", 1996-2006 (Box-folder 55.3)
  - Rockwell Publications, 1960-2010 (Box-folder 55.4)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1980-1990 (Box-folder 55.5)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1980-1990 (Box-folder 55.6)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1990-2010 (Box-folder 56.1)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1990-2010 (Box-folder 56.2)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1990-2010 (Box-folder 56.3)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, circa 1990-2010 (Box-folder 56.4)
  - Rockwell Speeches, 1996-2009 (Box-folder 56.5)
  - Rockwell Speech Notes, circa 1998-1999 (Box-folder 57.1)
  - Satin, Mark, The Mark Satin Report/Radical Middle, 1999-2004 (Box-folder 57.2)
  - Scientific Integrity, 1979-2007 (Box-folder 57.3)
  - Scientific Integrity, 1986-2003 (Box-folder 57.4)
  - Scientific Papers and Articles (assorted), 1973-2007 (Box-folder 57.5)
  - Simon, Julian L., 1983-1984 (Box-folder 57.6)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority, 1986 (Box-folder 57.7)
  - Technology and Society, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 57.8)
  - Terrorism, 1981-1994 (Box-folder 57.9)
  - Terrorism, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 58.1)
  - Terrorism, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 58.2)
  - Terrorism, 2003-2010 (Box-folder 58.3)
  - Three Mile Island Disaster, 1981-2001 (Box-folder 58.4)
  - United Nations Scientific Committee on the Effects of Atomic Radiation: "Sources and Effects of Ionizing Radiation", 1994 (Box-folder 58.5)
  - U.S. Department of Energy National Energy Strategy, 1990 (Box-folder 58.6)
  - U.S. Department of Energy National Energy Strategy, 1991-1998 (Box-folder 58.7)
  - Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research, "International Organizational Agreements for the united States Proposal for a Verified Agreement to Halt Production of Fissionable materials for Weapons Purposes", 1966 (Box-folder 59.1)
  - Washington Center of Foreign Policy Research, "International Organizational Arrangements to Verify Compliance with Arms Control and Disarmament Agreements", 1966 (Box-folder 59.2)
  - World Nuclear Association, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 59.3)
  - World Nuclear University Summer Institute, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 59.4)
- Parapsychology, 1924-2011; Series VIII
  Series VIII is comprised of materials collected and generated by Rockwell pertaining to the field of parapsychology. Topics include conciousness studies; extrasensory perception; psychokinesis; healing (energy, faith, psychic, etc.); acupuncture, chiropractic, and Rolfing; homoeopathy, dietary supplementation, and herbal remedies; dowsing; energy manipulation; forecasting; time manipulation; and UFOs, alien abductions, and extraterrestrial life.
  The series is comprised largely of promotional and informational materials from organizations in the field of parapsychology including interest and research groups, manufacturers and retailers, and educational programs. Organizations represented in this series include the Academy of Religion and Psychical Research, the Academy of Spirituality and Paranormal Studies, the Institute for Noetic Sciences, the International Society for the Study of Subtle Energies and Energy Medicine, the Monroe Institute, and the Parapsychological Association. The series also reflects Rockwell's role as Vice President of the United States Psychotronic Association and advisory council member of the National Institue of Discovery Science. Personalities within the parapsychology community featured in the Rockwell Papers include Anne Gehman, Christopher Bird, Cleve Backster, Robert A. Nash, James Randi, Dean Radin, Robert Jahn, and Rhea White. Of particular note is an extensive collection of materials documenting Rockwell's friendship with Bruce and John Klingbeil, a father-son pair of faith healers and founders of Spindrift, Inc., a research group based out of Salem, Oregon. Materials include publication drafts, cassette tapes, and informational materials from Spindrift and the Grayhaven School of Christian Science Nursing, as well as correspondence addressing the Klingbeils' faith healing research and personal struggles within the First Church of Christ, Scientist, the publication of The Spindrift Papers, and the deaths and legacy of the two men.
  Included in this series are correspondence, newsletters, serial publications, informational materials, and advertisements from numerous organizations and educational programs, and an extensive body of newsclippings. Also included is a dream journal kept by Rockwell from 1975-1976, a notebook recording experiments in psychokinesis conducted by Rockwell with celebrity psychic Anne Gehman, and a small collection of bent spoons. The series also includes records from Rockwell's robust publishing history focusing on the relationship between science and parapsychology.
  - Academy of Religion and Psychical Research, Academy of Religion and Psychical Research Bulletin, 2005 (Box-folder 59.5)
  - Academy of Religion and Psychical Research, Journal of Religion and Psychical Research, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 59.6)
  - Academy of Spirituality and Paranormal Studies, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 59.7)
  - Academy of Spirituality and Paranormal Studies, The Journal of Spirituality and Paranormal Studies, 2006-2008 (Box-folder 59.8)
  - Academy of Spirituality and Paranormal Studies, The Searchlight, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 60.1)
  - Acupuncture, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 60.2)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1970-1986 (Box-folder 60.3)
  - American Field Service, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 60.4)
  - American Society for Information Science, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 60.5)
  - American Society for Psychical Research, 1976-2004 (Box-folder 60.6)
  - American Society of Dowsers, 1975-2001 (Box-folder 60.7)
  - American Society of Dowsers, The American Dowser, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 60.8)
  - American Society of Dowsers, The American Dowser, 2007-2011 (Box-folder 61.1)
  - Audio Equipment, circa 1980 (Box-folder 61.2)
  - Backster, Cleve, 1974-1996 (Box-folder 61.3)
  - Bioacoustics, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 61.4)
  - Biofeedback, 1969-1994 (Box-folder 61.5)
  - Brain Development and Cognition, 1979-1999 (Box-folder 61.6)
  - Chiropractic, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 62.1)
  - Committee for the Scientific Investigation of Claims of the Paranormal, 1977 (Box-folder 62.2)
  - Consciousness, 1960-1988 (Box-folder 62.3)
  - Consciousness, 1972-2000 (Box-folder 62.4)
  - Consciousness, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 62.5)
  - Consciousness, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 62.6)
  - Consciousness, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 63.1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 63.2)
  - Correspondence, 1976-2000 (Box-folder 63.3)
  - Dietary Supplements and Herbal Remedies, 1973-1983 (Box-folder 63.4)
  - The Disclosure Project, 2001 (Box-folder 63.5)
  - Dowsing, 1975-1999 (Box-folder 63.6)
  - Dream Journals, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 63.7)
  - Edelson, Edward. Who Goes There? uncorrected proof, 1979 (Box-folder 63.8)
  - Electromagnetism, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 64.1)
  - Energy Medicine, 1978-2006 (Box-folder 64.2)
  - Energy Medicine, 1972-1986 (Box-folder 64.3)
  - Energy Transmutation, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 64.4)
  - Ethics, 1955-1992 (Box-folder 64.5)
  - Extrasensory Perception, 1966-2001 (Box-folder 64.6)
  - Extrasensory Perception, 1976-1996 (Box-folder 64.7)
  - Extrasensory Perception, 1979-1991 (Box-folder 65.1)
  - Faith Healing, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 65.2)
  - Future Studies and Forecasting, 1977-2008 (Box-folder 65.3)
  - Gehman, Anne, 1986 (Box-folder 65.4)
  - Grant Funding, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 65.5)
  - Grayhaven Publishing, The Home Catacomb, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 65.6)
  - Healing (General), 1970-1988 (Box-folder 65.7)
  - Healing (General), 1976-1986 (Box-folder 66.1)
  - Healing (General), 1976-1999 (Box-folder 66.2)
  - Healing (General), 1977-2008 (Box-folder 66.3)
  - Holistic Healing, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 66.4)
  - Homeopathy, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 66.5)
  - Institute for Information Studies, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 66.6)
  - Institute for Noetic Sciences, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 66.7)
  - Institute of Noetic Science, "Beyond Conflict" Symposium, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 67.1)
  - International Association for Near-Death Studies, Inc., 1990-2005 (Box-folder 67.2)
  - International Association for New Science, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 67.3)
  - International Parascience Institute, 19881-1983 (Box-folder 67.4)
  - International Platform Association, 1992 (Box-folder 67.5)
  - International Society for the Study of Subtle Energies and Energy Medicine, 1991-2005 (Box-folder 67.6)
  - International Society for the Study of Subtle Energies & Energy Medicine, Bridges, 1994-2006 (Box-folder 67.7)
  - International Society for the Study of Subtle Energies and Energy Medicine, Subtle Energies & Energy Medicine, 2004-2006 (Box-folder 67.8)
  - International Society for the Study of Subtle Energies and Energy Medicine, Subtle Energies & Energy Medicine, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 68.1)
  - Jahn, Robert, 1983 (Box-folder 68.2)
  - JFK University Graduate School of Consciousness Studies, 1977-1986 (Box-folder 68.3)
  - Kirlian Photography, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 68.4)
  - Kirlian Photography, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 68.5)
  - Kirlian Photography, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 69.1)
  - Kirlian Photography, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 69.2)
  - Life Energy, 1975-1991 (Box-folder 69.3)
  - Mankind Research Foundation / Mankind Research Unlimited, 1973-1989 (Box-folder 69.4)
  - Meteorology, Weather Control, and Solar Activity, 1954-1987 (Box-folder 69.5)
    Includes 7 microfiche.
  - Monroe Institute of Applied Sciences, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 69.6)
  - National Institute for Discovery Science, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 69.7)
  - National Institute for Discovery Science, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 70.1)
  - National Institute of Discovery Science, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 70.2)
  - National Institute for Discovery Science, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 70.3)
  - Neuro-Linguistic Programming, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 70.4)
  - Newsletters, 1974-2006 (Box-folder 70.5)
  - Orgone Energy, circa 1980 (Box-folder 70.6)
  - Parapsychological Association, Inc., 1975-1998 (Box-folder 70.7)
  - Parapsychological Association, Inc., 1976-1984 (Box-folder 71.1)
  - Parapsychological Association, Inc., 1980-2003 (Box-folder 71.2)
  - Parapsychology Publication Lists, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 71.3)
  - Parapsychology Reference Sources, 1969-1995 (Box-folder 71.4)
  - Parapsychology Research and Education Programs, 1973-2008 (Box-folder 71.5)
  - Parapsychology Research and Education Programs, circa 1975-1990 (Box-folder 72.1)
  - Parapsychology Research and Education Programs, 1976-2001 (Box-folder 72.2)
  - Plant Perception, 1971-1995 (Box-folder 72.3)
  - Presbyterian Church Lay Academy, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 72.4)
  - Princeton University Engineering Anomalies Research, 1984-1995 (Box-folder 72.5)
  - Princeton University Psychophysical Research Laboratories, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 72.6)
  - Psiline Database System, 1991-1996 (Box-folder 73.1)
  - Psi Search "Dialogues with Parapsychologists" Conference, 1979 (Box-folder 73.2)
  - Psychic Healing, 1962-1990 (Box-folder 73.3)
  - Psychic Healing, 1976-1999 (Box-folder 73.4)
  - Psychokinesis, 1976-1994 (Box-folder 73.5)
  - Psychokinesis Experiment Notebook, 1983-1994 (Box-folder 73.6)
  - Psychokinetically Altered Spoons, circa 1985 (Box 84)
  - Pyramid Energy, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 73.7)
  - Quantum Mechanics, 1979-2002 (Box-folder 73.8)
  - Quantum Mechanics, 1972-1989 (Box-folder 73.9)
  - Radiation Exposure in Space, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 74.1)
  - Randi, James, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 74.2)
  - Religion and Science, 1924-1999 (Box-folder 74.3)
  - Religion and Science, 1971-1991 (Box-folder 74.4)
  - Religion and Science, 1981-2002 (Box-folder 74.5)
  - Religion and Science, 1989-2007 (Box-folder 74.6)
  - Research in Parapsychology, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 74.7)
  - Research in Parapsychology, circa 1977-1995 (Box-folder 75.1)
  - Rockwell Book Reviews, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 75.2)
  - Rockwell Public Interest Program, 1988 (Box-folder 75.3)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, 1975 (Box-folder 75.4)
  - Rockwell Publication Drafts, 1977-1999 (Box-folder 75.5)
  - Rockwell Publications, 1978-1996 (Box-folder 75.6)
  - Rockwell Publication: Parapsychology State-of-the-Art Report, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 75.7)
  - Rockwell Speeches, 1976-1994 (Box-folder 75.8)
  - Rockwell Speech Notes, circa 1990 (Box-folder 75.9)
  - Rolfing, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 76.1)
  - Science and Parapsychology, 1900-1983 (Box-folder 76.2)
  - Science and Parapsychology, 1972-1997 (Box-folder 76.3)
  - Science and Parapsychology, 1977-1994 (Box-folder 76.4)
  - Science and Parapsychology, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 76.5)
  - Serios, Ted, 1990 (Box-folder 76.6)
  - Sigma Xi, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 76.7)
  - Silva Mind Control International, Inc., circa 1973-1980 (Box-folder 76.8)
  - The Society for Basic Irreproducible Research, The Journal of Irreproducible Research, 1978 (Box-folder 77.1)
  - The Sourcebook Project, Science Frontiers, 2005-2008 (Box-folder 77.2)
  - Soviet Union Parapsychology Research, 1972-1985 (Box-folder 77.3)
  - Soviet Union Parapsychology Research, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 77.4)
  - Soviet Union Parapsychology Research, 1981 (Box-folder 77.5)
  - Society for Scientific Exploration, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 77.6)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1981-1993 (Box-folder 77.7)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1985-1993 (Box-folder 78.1)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1987-1996 (Box-folder 78.2)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1989-1991 (Box-folder 78.3)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1990 (Box-folder 78.4)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1990-1996 (Box-folder 78.5)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1990-1998 (Box-folder 79.1)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1993-1997 (Box-folder 79.2)
  - Spindrift, Inc., 1995-2002 (Box-folder 79.3)
  - Spindrift, Inc., circa 1995-2005 (Box-folder 79.4)
  - Spindrift, Inc. Audiocasettes, circa 1994 (Box 83)
    Digital copies of these items are made available for use in the SCARC reading room upon request.
  - Sweet, Bill, Radio Interview, circa 1996 (Box 83)
  - Time Manipulation, 1967-1981 (Box-folder 79.5)
  - UFOs, 1947-1989 (Box-folder 80.1)
  - UFOs, 1947-2001 (Box-folder 80.2)
  - UFOs, 1954-2002 (Box-folder 80.3)
  - UFOs, 1962-2004 (Box-folder 80.4)
  - UFOs, 1968-2001 (Box-folder 80.5)
  - UFOs, 1994-2002 (Box-folder 81.1)
  - UFOs, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 81.2)
  - UFOs, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 81.3)
  - UFOs, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 81.4)
  - U.S. Government, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 81.5)
  - United States Psychotronics Association, 1992-2007 (Box-folder 82.1)
  - University of Miami School of Continuing Education, "Science and Parapsychology in the 20th Century" Conference, 1976 (Box-folder 82.2)
  - Yes Educational Society, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 82.3)
- Electronic Records, 1945-2013; Series IX
  Series IX is comprised of approximately 8 gigabytes of electronic records which were created and collected by Rockwell between 2003 and 2013. These records, which were received on and transferred from one hard drive and three DVDS, contain photographs, draft publications, research materials, video recordings, and correspondence. Included are digitized historical reports and motion picture film documenting life and work at Oak Ridge; materials related to Rockwell's pro-nuclear advocacy work, including video of his testimony during a 2009 Republican Senate Conference hearing; family photographs; and materials from the filming of Rickover: The Birth of Nuclear Power. This content may be accessed in the Special Collections & Archives Research Center Reading Room.
  Also included are sixteen unidentified and unprocessed 3.5" floppy diskettes and 2 5.25" floppy diskettes. This content is currently unavailable to researchers.
  - Rockwell Personal Hard Drive, 2003-2013; MSS Rockwell 001; 2.88 gigabytes
    Ted Rockwell's personal hard drive comprises more than 3,000 files including 600 digital photographs documenting activities of the Rockwell family. Contents include drafts of books and articles; correspondence; reference materials such as Wikipedia pages, online news articles, and scans of documents and photographs; materials relating to Rockwell's publishing efforts; a video recording of Rockwell reading from Creating the New World; and photos and documents from the filming of Rickover: The Birth of Nuclear Power. Much of the content relates to Rockwell's pro-nuclear advocacy efforts and includes materials pertaining to the Fukushima Daiichi disaster, the New York Academy of Sciences publication Chernobyl: Consequences of the Catastrophe for People and the Environment, nuclear regulation, hormesis, and radiation saftey.
  - Testimony to Senate Republican Conference, June 22, 2009; MSS Rockwell 002; 3.23 gigabytes
    These files comprise a video recording of a Senate Republican Conference hearing investigating a proposed cap-and-trade national energy tax and the possible expansion of nuclear power in the United States. The hearing is chaired by Senator Bob Bennett (Utah). Rockwell is one of several experts to give testimony during the hearing.
  - Rickover Project: Video Footage and Documents, circa 1945-1955; MSS Rockwell 003; 986 megabytes
    This collection of electronic records is comprised of an untitled film and digital reproductions of several documents dating from the late 1940s and early 1950s. The film, which is approximately 1 hour and 20 minutes in length, is comprised of color footage taken at Oak Ridge between 1945 and 1951. The film documents the construction of the Poplar Creek bridge and other structures at Oak Ridge, views of the town and surrounding area, scientists working with a test pile, and the christening of the "Sunday Punch," a B-25 airplane purchased with funds collected from the workers of ORNL. The collection also comprises technical papers and correspondence relating to the development of nuclear-powered vessels by the U.S. Navy including reports created by Farrington Daniels, H. G. Rickover, N. J. Palladino, J. H. Frye, Jr., and Ted Rockwell between 1946 and 1949. The file also includes a scan of "The Nuclear Propulsion Plant of the USS Nautilus SSN-571," an article published in 1954 by the Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers.
  - Rickover Project: Photographic Stills, circa 1945-1955; MSS Rockwell 004; 1.10 gigabytes
    This collection of electronic records is comprised of 93 photographs taken at Oak Ridge during and after World War II. Included are photographs of an Army-Navy "E" Award ceremony, the Daniels Experimental Power Pile, the town of Oak Ridge, research and production facilities, and several Oak Ridge personnel including Arthur Snell, Alvin Weinberg, and Eugene Wigner.
  - Unidentified floppy disks, circa 1990 (Box 83)